# **Emmanuel Ogundipe**

(443) 565-2613 | abiolaemma2014@gmail.com | New York, NY Linkedin.com/Emmanuel | Medium.com/Emmanuel | Github.com/Emmanuel

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Solutions Architect with 400+ training hours and experience in cloud infrastructure and well-architected framework design, networking fundamentals, security, computer programming, data migration and management. Interested in pursuing a career that will allow the opportunity to excel in the cloud-based environment as an Associate Solutions Architect at AWS where the utilization of skills in Terraform, Linux, AWS Lambda, AWS CloudFormation, AWS CloudWatch, DevOps, AWS Virtual Private Cloud, microservices architecture as well as first-rate leadership, effective communication, management, Innovation, curiosity to learn more will add value to the operations at AWS. Looking forward to applying direct experience and proficiency in cloud security, VMware, billing and account, traffic management in support of AWS and its mission for becoming a leader obsessed at solving customers' problems and provide for their needs.

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Kroger Manufacturing** 

Oct. 2020 - Dec. 2021

## **Operations Supervisor**

- Optimized production by 15% through updating planning inventory, and monitoring production metrics
- Reduced onboarding time for new hires by 10% by designing training programs for incoming associates

Crothall Healthcare - Cincinnati Children's Hospital

Dec. 2019 - Aug. 2020

## **Environmental Services Operations Manager**

- Increased performance and productivity by 15% by maintaining company's medical equipment
- Prevented potential injury and litigation by developing a strategy to control used battery waste hazard

Tradebe Environmental Services, LLC

Jul. 2019 – Aug. 2019

# Technical Chemist (Internship)

- Saved over \$100,000 in overtime costs by identifying, packaging, and labelling of waste chemicals
- Prevented regulatory fine of over \$4000 by completing all the DOT paperworks in a timely manner

Miami University

Aug. 2017 – Dec. 2019

### Graduate Research Assistant

- Reduced illegal dumping of wastes by applying the Community Based Social Marketing technique
- Performed evaluated on students' academic progress and performance using data analytic tools

Association of African Universities

Oct. 2016 - Nov. 2016

### Social Media Reporter/Analyst

- Tracked story metrics for insights and analysis on what works and what can be improved
- Maintained an active social media presence and managed the traffic to ensure a free flow of information

K-Peculiar Inc.

Jan. 2014 – June 2016

# Technical Sales Support Engineer

- Increased ROI by 5% by performing software and hardware upgrades and installations
- Provided troubleshooting support solutions in a timely manner to clients which improved customer satisfaction

St. Brigid's Computer Science Institute

Feb. 2005 - Sept. 2008

# Technical Training Specialist

- Trained and evaluated students in operating systems, enterprise software, networking and databases, computer programming which increased computer literacy among the adults and youths by 25%
- Provided technical support to the students assigned to remote locations by using Remote Desktop Protocols

# **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

• Miami University, 2019 Master of Environmental Science

• University of Ibadan, 2015

Master of Science in Criminology

• AWS Solutions Architect - Associate, 2022 Credential I Validate

• AWS Certified Cloud Practitioners, 2022 Credential I Validate

• Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, 2022 Credential ID: RFPQELGJS9XD Validate

• Generation USA, 2022 Cloud Practitioner Tech Accelerator Program

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Created An AWS Custom VPC**

- Enabled a DNS Homepage
- Created Private and public subnet and configured the route table

## **Scaled an AWS RDS Database**

- Scaled Db Horizontally by extending the database operations to additional nodes
- Scaled Db Vertically simply by changing the instance types
- Created Read Replicas
- Created AWS Backups for DR

# Created an AWS S3 bucket and migrated existing website to S3 $\,$

Static Web page project

Static Web Hosting on AWS S3 to improve web application reliability

# **SKILLS**

- AWS CloudFormation
- AWS Systems Manager
- AWS CloudWatch
- AWS CloudTrail
- Docker
- AWS Container Services
- Kubernetes
- CI/CD (Jenkins)
- AWS NoSQL (DynamoDB)
- Terraform

- Windows server
- Linux
- SQL
- Python
- DevOpsBash Scripts
- PowerShell
- CLI basics
- IT Support
- Git

- VMware
- Team Member
- Innovative
- Collaborating
- Interpersonal skills
- Articulating
- Ability to learn quickly
- Adaptability
- Bias for Action

# **AWARD**

- Received the Amazon Web Services (AWS) All Builders Welcome Grant as a participant at the AWS re:Invent 2022
- Received an award of recognition from the Ohio General Assembly shortly after graduation as one of the best graduating students in Miami University's Institute for the environments and sustainability. Also, a recipient of Thesis and Research Dissertation Award in 2018